Oh, it's not breaking news. They're a different basketball team with a healthy hole LeBron James
15 games over 500 when he's healthy three games under 500
Creates offense for himself and his teammates. They need him. They all Jeff Steph Curry what he's done over the past month and a half
Has been absolutely brilliant. He's as valuable as any player in this league
They play great defense and they have the ultimate home run hitter
Up beneath the team. It hasn't been easy this season
But both finished up the regular season strong the Lakers ended with a five game winning streak
And the Warriors ended with a six game winning streak
Watch out James again with that right ankle. He played last couple of games did tweak it on Sunday
But he played very well in those final two games
And here's one of the fun matchups in this series Anthony Davis has to take a tough shot well defended by dream on green
I
Obviously both teams would love to get the win tonight and give a little extra time to heal and prepare for their opponent
As Andrew Wiggins gets inside and gets the bucket
To me. He's the key. They need
25 from him tonight to be able to score enough
to win
Shruder nice play and drumming
Well a big flush down the other end and that's a welcome sight for Laker fans
It's not Anthony Davis and LeBron James making every play but you get Shruder making plays for drumming. They can be dangerous
Can face more for three. That's good
You know Steve Kerr talking before the game knows it's a taunting test
Against a Laker team when healthy they're as good as anybody in the league
But he also knows just one game. That's all you have to win. This is not a playoff series. It's a one game and move on
Shruder's jumper ball tipped and taken by dream on green
On the season Warriors 39 and 33, but they finished
Winning 15 of their final 20 games in the regular season just great basketball as Wiggins
Knocks down another and he's playing with a lot more confidence. Look at that
He didn't wait for Steph Curry to make a play waved everybody out of the way and took advantage of his matchup
James to Davis Davis goes right at dream on green again. Well defended Davis thought he was hit
Lakers have not been dominant at home this season clearly a lot of that had to do with missing the two players
As curry pulls back but despite all the misses says dream on green kicks it out to bays more and bays more from the elbow jumper way off
Looney has to throw it up and hit the ram and it goes in Kavan looney very aware of the shot clock about to expire
But Jeff you talked about
Without Anthony Davis and LeBron James you were impressed as Shruder misses impressed the way the Lakers kept being competitive
Absolutely defensively they remained rock solid. They just had some troubles offensively
But what they've done defensively all year to be the best team in the league at that end
is special
Curry throws the pass stolen by Anthony Davis and number one rated defensive team
Davis for three
Rebound kept alive by drumming, but he's gonna be called for a loose ball foul
Andre drumming signed at the end of March after a buyout
With the Cavaliers
This is his 22nd game start at all 21 games average just under 12 points little over 10 rebounds
But Frank Vogels is still a work in progress trying to get him comfortable and familiar with playing with his new teammates
Curry to looney
Curry using a dream on green screen nice feet inside looney shot block
Andre Chumman with the rejection looney was ready to throw it down
James to Davis
James with the tip in with a left hand and Frank Vogels I rate he thought David Davis got fouled again. I thought it was a good block
Curry flips it up shot too strong looney back out to Baysmore wide open three
And Vogel wants a timeout hot start
Such so many different matchups to look at and have fun. Let's let's start with Steph Curry Jeff
How do the Lakers try and guard him? What do you think their their game plan will be?
Well, the thing I think for a great defensive team like the Lakers that they have to avoid is
Overreacting to Curry and leaving others open. That's what's happened to start this game
Be well mark a big question for Frank Vogel and the Lakers they've got the size advantage
They've got the traditional centers Golden State likes to play small ball. How do you handle that if you're Frank?
Well, to me. I like to see him post up LeBron James. It's a smaller
Wiggins are last possession Baysmore defending him take advantage of that size of strength creating offense for himself as an aggressive
Offers teammates Wiggins has had a terrific year defensively in the Golden State the fifth rated defense in the NBA this year
Oh and Wiggins with the block of James has to fire it up and it's the side of the backboard great defensive play from Andrew Wiggins
This is a great defensive play coach, but if my opinion LeBron lets him off the hook. He fades away
There's no help coming. That's one-on-one beat him on your terms go towards the basket as opposed to fading away from absolutely
Wiggins had a strong finish to the season especially after the all-star break not only the defense but averaging over 20 per game
Ball deflected by Caldwell Pope
Wiggins guarded by James down the other end knocks down the three
Pretty good couple of sequences for Andrew Wiggins to start his play-in game. He's had a tremendous year
I mean like when he's the third most important player like he was in Minnesota the year
They went to the playoffs when he was there. It's a perfect role for him. I mean he's played exceptional basketball this year
Particularly the second half of the year
Drummond puts it on the floor double team back out to Davis shot clock down a three James a three-pointer way off
And dream on bringing the rebound the Lakers have missed nine of their first 11 from the field
Bayes more running gets it a Looney and Looney and a hell ball with Anthony Davis
I'm just thinking about it think about your third best player with the ability to average 20 to 25 points
You put Clay Thompson with this unit watch out next year
Absolutely and I give Steve Kerr a lot of credit. He's narrowed his rotation. They play eight guys now
There's more comfort level. They're an older team. They're experienced
You don't go far in the NBA playoffs playing all young guys
You saw Clay Thompson there once that injury changed a lot of plans for the Golden State Warriors
James now guarded by Bayes more Wiggins helps out shooter good ball movement here called while Pope good luck knocks down the three
And that's what they want out of that double team. I would rather stunt at Anthony Davis
Stay at home with called while Pope and make Anthony Davis shoot and make threes
You see shooter initially on Steph Curry. There'll be a number of players James with the deflection, but Wiggins able to get it back
Shot clock down to four Wiggins pull up three
And Drummond rips down the rebound drum and one of the premier elite rebounders in the game throughout his career
called well Pope off balance
James goes down to laying the runner and draws the foul on Bayes more
Well, they get the switch and then they double and they full rotate
That's a long closeout by Wiggins again. I would have rather stunted off of
Called well Pope and made Anthony Davis shoot the long ball and Mike. Did we have starting line-ups earlier? Yes?
I wish they were sponsored by Taco Bell and I could have said sponsored by Taco fall
I'm surprised you waited so long to take your first shot man. You didn't come up for breath
So I was I've been sitting on that
It's the free throw, but congratulations to you on truly a Hall of Fame career. It was an honor to be at your induction
Absolutely well deserved and an incredible speech. You made us proud partner. Thank you gentlemen, but this is a fact
I couldn't have done it without you man. We don't need to hear that. That's fake hustle. That's like saying
Curry couldn't have done it without
Jordan Bell come on
Why can't you just say thank you do as well? Thank you. No, no, you don't mean that. Don't say thank you
He's not sincere man. It's about him
Warriors lead by six
Shruder guarding curry again curry launches a three-pointer that one off the bar for the rebound want to Scott O Anderson
Dream on green tries a three that this is drumming Halls in another rebound
Michael Mulder also in the game for Golden State. Here's Bayes more
Mulder runs to the corner, but Bayes more banks it won't go to Scott O Anderson misses the tip. Here comes James
Shruder corner three James the offensive rebound
Quick move inside draws the contact shot won't go but a foul and he will go right back to the free throw line
But I don't want to sound like a broken record, but that's the type of plays
He's got to make especially the way that they're defending him and I understand coming off injuries trying to feel his way through the game
But as we move closer and closer towards getting involved into this game, I expect to see LeBron a little bit more aggressive
Now you see those two games the last two of the regular season did tweak again the ankle on Sunday, but nothing serious
Oh
James missing a career-high 27 games only played 45 games at those 20 consecutive out with the ankle injury
Now playing in the play-in game where he famously said whoever came up with this should be fired I
Think the whole thing has been pretty exciting curry on the drive
Flips it up back shot is good. Steph Curry with his first field goal
Oh, just look at the size difference between these two teams on the floor right now at every position
James finds called will pull another corner three another one knocking it down called will pull
Two for two from three-point range
Welcome back to Warriors Lakers
Now if you see LeBron James go to the bench a little more often than usual in this first half
Coach Frank Vogel told me that's because the more minutes LeBron plays the more his ankle tends to stiffen up
So they are going to try if they don't fall too far behind here to back load his minutes and keep him under 30 total
Now you just saw the playback in March where he got initially hurt
This is where he tweaked it again just three days ago LeBron told us he hasn't stopped thinking about the way this injury
Derailed his season. He had to rehab for more than six weeks and said quote
I hated every moment of it, but Mike he said he's ready to move forward and he doesn't anticipate his movement being limited in any
Real way tonight
Thank You Rachel you forget how well he was playing
Prior to the injury how well the Lakers were playing prior to the injury to James and David. They were 21 and 6
Caruso wide open nobody near him and he cans the three
and they did on that one stay at home on Caldwell Pope, but
Caruso shot the ball very well from three this year
Dream on green gets inside and draws the foul
Andre drumming
Green shaking up
Well good stunt by Bayes more
but Caruso
Again really improved as a three-point shooter
So green will go to the line
Green has had an outstanding season especially defensively he gets the first-door upcoming national TV schedule team T tomorrow
Indiana and Washington
That game
After Indiana with the victory Washington losing to Boston then ESPN Friday Memphis will play the loser of this game
It's a nine Eastern start and will be either in San Francisco or here at the Staples Center
Tell you Indiana played a great
Offensive game down three of their main guys so bonus
He's a great great offensive player. Absolutely
They started off great and did not let their foot off the gas pedal Davis after kuzma Kyle kuzma Montrez Harrell in the game
Dream on green on Davis one-on-one excellent defense again stolen by Bayes more
Bayes more goes right at Davis throws up a wild shot and draws the foul Anthony Davis picking up his first
That is outstanding defense by Dream on green one-on-one against Anthony Davis for the second time
You just you just battle them
And you stay in front and don't give them anything easy active hands
Secure your position be disciplined and give your team a chance exactly what he did
Well Bayes more in the starting lineup
As Golden State has some injuries Kelly Ubrey still out with a left wrist
He's gonna be reevaluated next week James Wiseman, of course
They're center out for the season with right knee surgery Damien Lee also out and of course that man missing his second consecutive year
Can't wait to see him back in uniform running up and down the floor
And they need him and you look at this game for example the war is not gonna win if Steph Curry
Doesn't get going at some point the Lakers are forcing him to get rid of the basketball way he sees bodies in front of
The Scott Anderson misses the three called wallpult the rebound
They're doing a good job of keeping two people he comes off a pick and roll. They don't leave them until he gets rid of the basketball
Stuff Curry's taking just three shots so far
Mulder some early minutes guard in Caruso
Fall will pull my screen set by Davis
Step back jumper won't go
Green has been absolutely great defensively
Curry against Kuzma, there's a double team second turnover by Curry
Kuzma to Caruso drives inside lefty lamp as good as goes crashing
Fogel again saying where is the whistle a lot of contact there? And
Caruso off the bench with five points
Active hands come up with the steal and good delivery by Kuzma
Rousseau with the finish that's clearly contact. He should be going to the line
Curry doubled again
Graham on green fakes Davis right there
524 Curry fakes the three gets away from Davis off one foot too strong
And here comes Kuzma
Lakers have made it difficult early for Steph Curry
Kuzma a three-pointer
And a loose ball fouls gonna go against Curry
And coach, you know people say well, how can you get them going?
Well, you can get them going by getting stops defensively and pushing the basketball is tough for the trap pick and rolls
When you're pushing it in transition and a technical foul, I believe on dream on green
No green Josh Tivens saying I don't want to hear it
We now trying to talk
Whatever happened to the parent that says I don't want to hear and then you still talking they said I said I don't want to hear
That's the end of it. He just gave him an extra candy bar
That foul by the way was on Mulder not Curry as Davis hits the technical free throw and now
Much more pleasant conversation
Josh Tiven and I have a difference of opinion of what no more means
Josh Tim has become one of the premier officials in the NBA in recent years
And you get a technical and since we don't count this as the playoffs it doesn't count against any suspension so you can
These are freebies
Sure, they're in there up top to Caruso
And throws that advanced he was talking about the playing stats do not count toward the regular season and do not count toward the playoffs
They kind of fade away, I suppose, but it's also, you know, it's the same for the broadcast. So whatever you say
It's okay. You can say whatever you want. It's not it's not recorded. He does that anyway, Mike. I'm just saying they should count I
Saw Jason Tatum's 50 as Mulder dumps it counts
Put him in the postseason. This is the postseason. I'm in agreement with you
I think they're they're trying to figure out. What's the best way? I just figured it out for him
I'm just saying what they're thinking curry on the rebound. Oh, Davis is miss curry way downtown in and out
And Davis the rebound
Lakers shooting just 32% from the field, but they're only down by three
Montrez Harrell spins flips it up shot won't go
Tipped by Kuzma and another offensive rebound which he's been doing all season
Schroeder misses the three
And curry the rebound curry average the career high five and a half rebounds per game this year gets inside draws the foul counter and one
And to me that's the most underrated two things about his game the rebounding aspect and the finishing aspect
That's just beautiful
Touch around the rem this year he became the oldest scoring champion in the NBA in 23 years
When Michael Jordan was 35 he finished the season with 46 points on Sunday against Memphis
He was just absolutely sensational of course a lot of the talk this week LeBron James saying the other day about stuff curry
He's the MVP. He had the best season all year
Well, he's had an incredible season and it's it's a joy to cover him and watch him as Davis knocks down the little floater
He was 0 for 6 Sanford. He Davis before that shot and it's back to 4
But I like what he did instead of posting screen on the ball and get some space from green
Well on to Scott. Oh Anderson knocks down a three turns and says something to the fans and runs down the floor
He has one been a one of the great stories this year in the NBA
East Oakland native now playing for his team and he grew up rooting for
Shrooder shot blocked to Scott. Oh Anderson saves it, but right the Herald blocked by green but a foul
And two free throws coming up for LA
See the great ball movement and young fella gets it done Oakland's finest
Proud to be a warrior
Well, there's happy ending for him. He just signed a multi-year contract to play for the team again. He
Growing up rooted for his undrafted out of Marquette back in 2015 took him five years to get to the NBA
Mexico Argentina then as well of the G League
And he has become so much more than an energy player Bob Myers absolutely loves him. He's got terrific skill
He's extremely smart Dreymon green says he changes the game with his intensity
And Steve Kerr says I trust him
Been a great story and he's the one guy that can do Dreymon green type things on the floor
initiating offense setting screens extra pass
What a fine by the Warriors
Steve Kerr actually calls him a mini Dreymon green
You think I just freestyled that Mike. Well, I wanted to give a little credit come on. Looney the rebound
six point Warriors lead
And it's about a five-second difference between the shot clock and game clock
Very just two for six to start
Mulder Wiggins
Rebound shooter final seconds no fouls to give here shooter ahead to Davis Davis three pointers up shot short
Welcome back to the State Farm NBA play in tournament. I'm Rachel Nichols here with coach Steve Kerr
Great start you guys got out to Steve. What was working for you?
Well, I thought our defense was really good Rachel and it's been good, you know the last few weeks
And that's that's what we have to play off of so our guys did a good job
What's your approach to the size disadvantage that your team has here tonight?
Well, we just got to make sure everybody's engaged all the time and you know keeping everyone off the glass there
They're obviously
Much bigger and stronger than we are
But if we're active and we're boxing out with all five guys we can hold our own
Thanks so much Steve. Thanks you Mike. Thank you, Rachel fifth turnover for Golden State
James five points in that first quarter Taylor and Horton Tucker out there with James shooter Kuzma and Harold
Horton Tucker straight on three. That's good. This young man's having
An excellent season in terms of taking some steps, but the three-pointer has been at times a struggle for him a nice shot there
And it's a three-point game
Jordan pull the floater
Looney's follow misses Harold the rebound no curry no green with James on the floor
This is gonna be a challenge
James drives can't get it Kavan Looney grabs another rebound seven rebounds already for Kavan Looney
They'll need him with the size advantage of the Lakers
Mulder catch and shoot that's good three-pointer from Mulder. He can shoot the second-year guard from Kentucky
Well, you look at this unit on the floor for the Warriors right now
No curry a green but they have the ability to compete at a high level spread the floor and they have shooting all around
Shrooder drives shooter misses Looney grabs another defensive rebound
And interestingly they have Toscano Anderson on shrooder
Pull has it eight to shoot Toscano Anderson
Not that time fight for the rebound Kavan Looney nine rebounds now already another three
Mulder can't get it to go
Six-point goal and state lead were two minutes into the second
They played each other three times warriors won the first game
Lakers two blowouts after that, but both teams obviously so radically different now
Kuzma
And it hit one of the wires atop the backboard so it's golden state ball
Stop curry talking about the the Warriors. She said back in in February or March
It was a little bleak, but he's so proud of the way this team just kept fighting
And he says now we've given our children's elves a chance to make this season matter curry and green the leadership
They showed
The Warriors turned it around
Toscano Anderson feet inside
Looney shot in and out LeBron James rips down the rebound that's outstanding possession of great ball movement making place for one another
It just wasn't able to finish at Toscano Anderson like you mentioned before mark and really
Pass and make plays
Montrez Harrell
foul by Looney
And the former six-man winner with the Clippers will go to the line
It has not been an easy adjustment for Montrez Harrell last year played so well for the LA Clippers this year
He's had some some good stretches his numbers are solid not playing as many minutes not getting as much touches
But it's been inconsistent at times well three centers makes it a challenge for the coaching staff and for the three players
And I think the thing if I'm if I'm Harold my mentality has got to be the way I got paid and made it in this league
I gave great energy great effort great enthusiasm from day one
So I was a difference maker because of the way I went about my business
He's got to get back to being that then he's a handful to defend
And I think it's interesting too. I think the challenge going forward
For the coaching staff is at times last year
They played with as a free throw rebounds given up they played with Anthony Davis at center
So now that they have three other centers
Do you ever get back to that lineup right? It's basically four centers that all feel they deserve time Horton Tucker goes inside flips it up
And an offensive foul is called
Tucker picks up the personal Frank Vogel obviously disagrees with the call Horton Tucker wants to see the replay
Not a lot there
To me that's not a defensive foul, but it's not an offensive foul either
Pull to Wiggins Wiggins trying to slam it shot block Horton Tucker right there minimum of the rim and then a foul
As Wiggins goes crashing to the floor
I like Wiggins trying to attack like that
Attacking the rim
Good job of going vertical
But I like like you talked about here
They need him to be aggressive on the offensive end
That was on Caruso
Caruso picks up his first
Here's pool and pool is foul before any shot attempt Caruso trying to fight over the screen picks up his second
And I agree with the lake is defensive right now
You have to treat Jordan pool the way you treat Steph Curry with that first unit because he's a guy that can get hot and then the rim opens up for
Well the last six games averaged 20 a game
He had a career high 38 last week
Now with Curry on the bench Frank Volko said he's kind of taken over that like the CJ McCullum role in terms of when Lillard goes to the bench
McCullum has to score they need pool to score
Not that time as Kuzma gets the rebound
Not that he was comparing him to CJ McCullum
Horton Tucker short on the three
Here's pool inside the arc
Six on the 24
Wiggins against Caruso
Nice spin move and finish from Andrew Wiggins. He's got nine points. He has a great right to left spin
Harold knocked away ball picked up to Scott Landerson two on one break goes right at LeBron James and finishes
And a timeout call by Frank Vogel
They got a lot of doubt down there. We got we got a lot of belief the job guys good quarter good quarter
All they are on on the boards
defending without fouling all good stuff
He has been proud of this team talked about, you know disjointed early obviously the injury to play Thompson
He said that they've come together really well as a season when on he kept telling the team late in the season
We're gonna go on a run. We're gonna go on a run and they finished 15 and five in those last 20 games
And I like how Wiggins is picking up full court on occasions James drives gets inside blocked by just kind of Anderson knocked out of bounds
Still Laker ball
This is just good verticality boys kid is tough
Warriors have five block shots already
James gets inside bank shot missed it ball chipped out to scana Anderson pushing it up the floor
Mulder pool to scana Anderson out there with Looney and Wiggins Wiggins fires a three way off
And it's Laker ball and you look at this game right now with seven minutes to go in in the second quarter
One team is getting after it like they wanted and the other team is in chill mode
And if you're the Lakers you have to respond because the Warriors are here to advance to Sunday
Kuzma gets that one to go prior to that shot the Lakers were shooting 24% from the field. They had missed eight shots in a row
That's a very strong assertive move by Kuzma
Wiggins to Looney
Piscano Anderson can't get the three Montrez Harrow
with the board
James finds Montrez Harrow inside and throws it down in a crowd
This first field goal
Timeout call by Steve Kerr
The Warriors are shooting 38% 29 from 3 and Steph Curry has five points
Now both these teams their defense has been a big part of their success as we mentioned Lakers number one defensive rating and the Warriors number five
Pool goes right at drumming layup is good top shot from Jordan pool
Lakers looking to push the other way Steve Kerr talked about that he wants his team to really push the tempo tonight
Trudder gets some room
Davis tries the three
Dave is a not shot the ball well from three since his return from the camp injury
Curry finds some room gets inside draws the foul banker won't go he's mad at himself
But he'll get two free throws and that's two straight pick and rolls that drumming has been ineffective in defending
He's got to get down a little bit lower. He has great feet
He can do this
But he can't reach and get himself out of position
Curry has talked this year, it's the best he's felt physically and the best he is seen the game this year
And the year off last year
Might have helped that as well only five games played with a broken hand
There's no question it re-energized and you know players will talk about this guys who play in the finals year after year the grind of that LeBron James
That's one of the unbelievable things about what he's able to do. It's almost like another season
And it has recharged him
And a shrewder trying to get going still looking for his first field goal throws it away great with the steel
That's great pick-and-roll defense. I mean that's superior
Ability to play to play the ballhandler and play the roll man
You see shrewder he's got to come off the score green stunning at him and recovering
That's beautiful as I'll stand
Steve Kerr talks about all the time he knows what the opponent is running
He blows up opponents plays all the time nice feet inside but Bayes more rushed it
Although Davis's presence had something to do with that called well pulp three-pointer short right back to him up top the shooter
Call well Pope pass inside broke it up Bayes more this time got a hand on it boy active hands again from the Warriors pool
Explodes to the rim and finishes Jordan pull his second field goal and it's back to a 10-point Warriors lead
The Lakers have 30 points and there's under five to play in the first half
Shooter fakes
Caruso barely had it his hand knocks down the three I'm looking at that last possession Anthony Davis has Kent Bayes
More on him and comes out the center high screen of rule the side screen of rule
Oh, give me the basketball it's your time to be a little bit more aggressive
That's kind of Anderson Bayes more fakes drives on Caruso leans in on drum and flips it up way off
And an offensive foul is gonna be called on Anthony Davis and Frank Bogle hot once again
Right now Dremont Green is putting on a master's class on how to defend
He has taken Anthony Davis out of the ballgame now, that's that's that's just a smart play
He puts himself in position to take the hit
But he is in the head of Anthony Davis thus far and some join going on right now and a technical fat
We'll hand it out double technical
John Goble came in I believe it's on Davis and Tuscano Anderson the Warriors are saying why is it a double technical?
Your dream on green you don't want to get caught in this you already have a technical foul yourself
So it is on Davis, but the other ones on pool Jordan pool
That's like the old line when the NCAA got really mad at Kentucky they put Cleveland State on probation
Currie for three his first three-pointer of the half and from way downtown
And it makes it a 10-point game again, but Davis is now at the five position
And LeBron James back in
Frooter 0 for 7 that's James Garda by Toscano Anderson
Leans in excellent defense throws it away boy this cold let's stay defense as you said Mark
They're putting on a clinic here in the first half
Five to shoot for the Lakers
Caruso shot clock winding down and pull with a foul with 3.4 remaining on the shot clock
Davis gets that one to go just his second field goal. He was 1 for 9 prior to that. It's an 8-point game
Despite the horrific shooting by the Lakers, especially their stars again. They're only down eight curry another three
Back to back threes for Steph Curry now. He's got 12
And this equals the largest lead of the first half
Wiggins back in now Curry switches on James two former MVPs
Davis against Wiggins
Davis settles for the jump shot in a rebound to Scott Anderson
Green beautiful pass ahead to Scott Anderson stripped by Caldwell Pope
Schroeder tries a three and Schroeder still without a field goal James to Davis Davis blocked green got a piece of it
And the Warriors go the other way
Another forced turnover by Golden State Curry gets inside blocked by Schroeder
Here comes Caruso the other way
Caruso
Almost tried an alley-oop to himself
Somehow managed to get the layup to go. He did alley-oop it to himself got away with it, which is fine
You can throw it up
But I'll tell you what green not giving James a dunk to me as
next-level intelligence
Dream on green cross court to pull pull for three knocks it down eight three-pointer for Golden State
Now the Golden State Warriors showing once again why they've been one of the best defensive teams in the NBA this season led by
Dream on green and guys you got a figure you've watched so much basketball. He's one of the smartest defensive players
I've seen it in all my years covering the NBA
Well, I had the privilege of coaching him so I'm well aware from day one his instincts his intelligence superior
True to the drive
Nearly another forced turnover, but Caldwell Pope has it and a whistle and a foul. Let's check in with Rachel
Mike this is so interesting according to all the tracking data. We have now if you look over the past eight years
No one has defended Anthony Davis on more plays than yep Dremond green
So Dremond told me that that means there's no surprises AD knows all of his little tricks
He knows all of Anthony's instead. He said quote what it's gonna boil down to win this game
It boils down to heart it boils down to who wants it more it boils down to who can outthink the guy other guy on a particular play
He said it's not that I will go and say I don't know what he's capable of
I know what he's capable of Dremond said it's can I stop him and as you guys have noted tonight
We've seen a clinic Dremond's been doing that work Mike
Thank you, Rachel as Wiggins picks up the foul James hits the free throw
He just seems to shine come playoff time
He lives for these type of games these type of matchups, but you know what he knows also coach. He knows that
And it's his advantage if it comes down to heart and it's no disrespect to Anthony Davis
But he has a fight his chance in that situation if it boils down to talent. It's Anthony Davis all day long
Lakers shooting 30% from the field
29% from three and they have 38 points with a minute and a half to play in the second curry three-pointer
Too strong rebound Caruso
Davis comes back to Caruso
Pull all over Caruso and his headband knocked now James and Wiggins
Caldwell pulp corner three is up shot no good and Wiggins with a rebound and great blockout by Toscano Anderson
You don't see blocking out
But he eliminated Davis's size with that blockout Wiggins nice turnaround shot wouldn't go James looks to lead the break the other way
Pass inside Caruso layup tough shot able to get it off the glass
Caruso is their leading score and they're only playing our double figures with 12
And that's a good sign of you the Golden State Warriors game plan this
And I'd like this lineup with Davis at five a
Lot more from a spacing standpoint
Pull cross cart Toscano Anderson with five to shoot and hits the three-pointer lawn Toscano Anderson eight points off the bench
Back to 12 with 25 seconds remaining
The three leading scores for the LA Lakers James Davis and Truder three for 27 from the field
Truder the drive left as good tough shot. He finally gets one to go. He was 0 for eight
And I'm not allowing Steph Curry to play one-on-one in this situation
Either are they Curry step back three bang at the buzzer
Steph Curry from downtown and the Warriors will take a 13-point lead into halftime
What a first half for Golden State
Defensively putting on a clinic and then Curry coming alive from three-point range in the second period
Bays more steps back three-pointer way off rebound Looney, but he's called for a push
Looney by the way had 11 rebounds in that first half as he picks up his second coach if I was Dennis Truder
The bronze James Anthony Davis looking at what we talked about the impact in that first half
I'd cut off the coach the coach's speech in the lockerman halftime and I look and say I've got to be better
I've got to do a better job of taking care of my business
Forget about what's on the board
Again considering those numbers. They're fortunate to be only down by 13 as we've seen in the NBA
13 points is not a huge deficit to overcome
There's a shot clocks down to four Schroeder drives on Wiggins
and a foul
I'll take it on the side
We'll send it over to Rachel
Well, Mike
I'm told there was plenty of excitement as the Warriors piled into the locker room coming off that great step shot to close the first half
But I'm also told it only lasted about 15 seconds and then Steve Kerr got everyone to buckle down and refocus
No major adjustments for the Warriors, but he did tell the team prepare for the Lakers to make some runs here
They're a championship team. We just have to weather them meanwhile over on the Lakers side
The coaching staff told players they got to be more physical against this Warriors squad
They do have that size advantage, but they also told the guys just relax. We're missing wide open shots. Just
Ease into it here. These are shots that you can make Mike
Thank you, Rachel is dream on green picked up the foul initially Josh Tiven said
It was on the floor but talked with his fellow officials. They changed it to the active shooting
No, he got bullied by LeBron James into asking. No, that's that's the real deal
That's another way of putting it and they changed the call and I'm not saying it wasn't the right call
I'm saying that's why they discussed it and I would have a different message for the Lakers
I wouldn't say relax. I would say we're too relaxed
Let's do something
No doubt Warriors look like the hungry team
Curry saves it the right to shoot her on an errand pass from green
And here comes James James gets into the paint mid-range jumper shot won't go loony another rebound quick outlet to Curry
Curry to base more attacks the rim layup shot. No good
Well the state looking to push it every opportunity
Shrooter draws the foul shot won't go but Steph Curry will pick up his second personal
And that's been a problem for Golden State all year, which is fouling too much
And to start this half
They haven't made them make shots. They put Shrooter to the line twice. Sure missed 14
Days down the stretch with the health and safety protocols played the last two games
But his conditioning is far from where it should be
I
Shrooter led the team in scoring when LeBron James was out mark they need him to be super aggressive
Absolutely out of pick and rolls in transition at their best. He's that third option and at times carries them offense
Curry to green green try to jam it James and drumming right there James down the other end lamp
A foul count it and one stolen down and a chance for a three-point play and suddenly it's just a seven-point game with a free throw
The coach a recipe for disaster if you're the Warriors
Allowing the Lakers to get to the free throw line turning the basketball over and giving them easy opportunities in transition
Sometimes teams in this league frustrate me
But what the Utah Jazz just did by giving out
52 full-ride scholarships to underserve kids is a home run that the whole league
Should adopt absolutely
When the players were calling the kids I looked at that video and I was
Absolutely so proud of Utah and the players. I just thought it was brilliant
So special for those young men and women as Wiggins spins and backs at home
Back up to eight for Golden State Warriors have led the entire game
Lakers have not led the largest lead
Is 13 right now 57 49 called well Pope to James James kicks it out
All well Pope off the bounce running lap is good sweet. Oh from contiguous called well Pope
He's got eight points and I like that offense of set by
Los Angeles having James as the screener
When he's the screener it is really hard to guard pick and roll curry behind the back flips it up
And went with short as Davis grabs the rebound and especially the screener with curry involved that puts in the dilemma defensively
James to Davis Davis three-pointer won't go
Lakers just five of 19 from downtown Nolan State has hit twice as many threes
Dangerous pass stolen by called well Pope called well Pope down the other end lay a block but a foul
Raymond Green upset after the turnover the called wall Pope will shoot a couple of free throws
But again when we're talking about a team that's struggling to score you're giving them opportunities
Carelessness on the offensive end by the Warriors and they're already the Lakers are already in the penalty
So they're shooting the rest of the quarter while la hasn't committed a team foul
No Golden State already five team fouls
You call well Pope's numbers
One of these teams tonight will earn the seventh seed in the West and the right to get into the NBA playoffs
And you can watch the NBA playoffs starting Saturday on ABC ESPN TNT and
NBA TV the winner tonight
Will face Phoenix
That game one will be Sunday time to be determined in Phoenix against the Suns
Just a spectacular season they finished second Utah finished one
These two teams in the playing
Shrooder against
Wiggins playing physical Wiggins spins tied up shot clock at five green another turnover
As Davis brings it into the front court back up Shrooder puts up the three puts it in
Dennis Shrooder just his second field goal, and it's a one-point game
You get into rhythm at the free throw line. So he caught a rhythm at the free throw line
And now he knocks in the three
And a foul down the other end crowd doesn't like it. There's about six thousand fans here at the Staples Center tonight
And this is just a wide open
Catching shoot three and Mike you mentioned six thousand fans. I also love
That they have they were able to get more fans because they have what a vaccinated section. Yep. I love that
Kari step back three pointer and his foul
Shrooder commits the personal that's gonna be his first and curry will shoot three free throws
And I thought he kicked out his leg I would really think about challenging that
He does get into that landing in
And like he talked about the winner playing the Phoenix Suns want to say congratulations to coach Monty Williams who the coaches
Voted him as the coach of the year. Yep this season in NBA a job. Well done and an award. Well deserved
Absolutely terrific job, and I love their whole team attitude. They weren't trying to to manipulate the standings a
Whoever comes our way comes our way
How about the season Chris Paul has had for that team?
Meanwhile these two coaches you will chess match right now
Curry hits all three lead back up to four 18 points for Curry as a successful coach in his league for so many years
Did you ever try to manipulate the standings and see who you was gonna match up with now? I just I had a
Like just whether I was right or wrong that whole karma
As Anthony Davis takes another three. I just didn't believe in it
I if you want to if you're if you're a championship mentality, I just think you got to play everybody
Blocked by Looney drum and try to get it to go
He thought he was fouled again the initial dream on green defense on Davis forced him to pass it
Wiggins step back jumper got it Andrew Wiggins now with 13 points. How about the move by Wiggins?
That's not an easy shot. Oh, but he's got that right to left spin
Wiggins one-on-one with LeBron James who's just two of nine from the field
Jumper is good
He's got to look at it like it's disrespectful as good a defend as Wiggins is you're gonna play me one-on-one
Recognize who I am take it personal
Shruder gets right up into Curry Curry splits the defense dangerous pass stolen by Caldwell Pope
That's nine turnovers
Now for the Warriors
Four of them already here in his third quarter. We played just five minutes
Shruder baseline jumper is short
Curry triple team finds Looney
Touch pass to Baysmore
Corner three is good Baysmore with his third three pointer
And now Frank Vogel wants a timeout the lead right back up to seven the 11 three pointer for Golden State
You know what I'd like to the sweatsuits that the Warriors are wearing with pan homage to Oakland
That's pretty that's pretty good. I love that
Drummond hands off Caldwell Pope and double team him Davis swings it now shooter across the lane shot clock down to seven
Truder giving some room
hesitated shot clock at two Caruso on the drive on the pull-up shot way off
And a 24 second violation another excellent defensive sequence from Golden State
But I thought Shruder cooperated he had a couple of shots that he turned down instead of being aggressive
And I'll tell you what I find interesting didn't they say
Before the game that they wanted to limit LeBron James to 28 or 30 minutes. He only has eight minutes left
He's sitting right now. He played 17 and a half minutes in the first half
And 22 overall so
Wiggins against Caruso Wiggins nice feet inside Looney gathers and throws up a shot off the glass just his second field goal
But Looney's played some excellent defense and he has 12 rebounds
And they missed him earlier in the possession by green on a slip
Drummond across the lane flips it up and in
Four points for Drummond
Curry gets away from the double team continues left-handed off the glass won't go chipped in by Kevon Looney
Looney part of those championship teams he's got the corporate knowledge
Drummond calling for one-on-one with Looney spins in the paint falls down lost it and Bayesmore foul by Shruder
And if I'm the Warriors, you're doing me a favor
Posting up drumming against Looney. I know he scored the last possession, but if I'm Anthony Davis
I've got a look to be aggressive and demand the basketball. This is not this is not a winning recipe coach
I I agree if you can get them to post drumming
That plays away from their strength, but again, I like this
Inserting the highly intense West Matthews and putting Anthony Davis at the center position
Matthews his first minutes tonight curry long distance. That's a three stuffed curry his fourth three pointer of the game
It's back up to a dozen
Toscano Anderson and Mulder back in now stripped by green and stolen ball loose picked up by curry knocked out of his hands by Caruso
Called well Pope to Caruso
Cross-court Matthews Matthews for three
Talk about an instant contribution
And that's a huge turn of events up 12 all the momentum going in transition curry turns it over and then a three
Caruso steal on that an important play
And then a foul called on called well Pope Frank Vogel. I rate again
I'm looking at the sideline and you see greatness and Drake and Michael B. Jordan just
Shaking their head as chef curry with the shot and the response Caruso to Matthews
knocked down shot
Given the Lakers life
Matthews in his first year and there they are
That it courtside dream on green block by Davis Anthony Davis sensational defensive play
And green usually gets a layup of game off that fake
To curry Davis calling for it gets it inside shots good at one
Davis at both ends and a chance for a three-point play
A coach is what you're talking about putting Davis at the five
So the screen and roll takes dream on green off of him puts a smaller Anderson on him
He can have his way gets the contact and the finish well, and there's room to move and post
Here he starts it off. That's a tremendous
Blockshot, but it starts with the lineup construction that with four perimeter players surrounding Davis
He can go in there without drumming or another center clogging it up
Anthony Davis only 36 games played during the regular season miss 36
30 of them with that right calf
He was starting to show signs last final games of the season at that 42 point game against Phoenix
He has struggled so far tonight, but still a long way to go
Six-point Warriors lead four minutes to play pass inside the curry missed the layup, but a foul
We got to show that that is brilliance moving without the basketball and not a foul a goal tending
That's right marks of two points for curry. It's just so good
What if more guys were willing to move at the speed and the consistency of curry they'd be rewarded too
Matthews misses
Curry stumbles a bit now keeps his dribble alive against Davis lost it ball deflected and a backcourt violation
Well Curry's been loose with the ball
This quarter, but this is brilliant comes off the initial screen sets it up like he's gonna come off the stagger back cuts
That's just
Well Anthony Davis was saying, you know usually when a guy gives up the ball the defender can relax a little bit
He goes, but that's when Steph Curry is his most dangerous after he gives up the ball
I know I said it before but think about it
You add clay Thompson who moves in a similar form and fashion the pressure that they put on your defense collectively
It's unmatched in the history of this game
Matthews to Davis scar to buy to scone o Anderson green looking to help
Davis spins contested shot way off that one at the side of the backboard and green gets the rebound a
Well-timed double team by green on the baseline side Davis now three for 16 to scone o Anderson pass the Baysmore
Lot of contact over in the far side Baysmore three point one go Davis the rebound
Under three to play here in the third
Alex Caruso goes all the way blocked by green Baysmore the other way
Tram on green again just putting on a defensive clinic
Plus six assists five rebounds gets inside layup. He missed it ball knocked that about still golden state ball green thought he was fouled
This Caruso turn in the corner
Sees green
That's outstanding defense and help by a Draymond green has been doing it all night long. That's his third block
Warriors have eight to shoot Jordan pulled his come in
The bronze aims back in
Pass inside a Wiggins stolen by James. That's the seventh turnover here in the third
They only had five the first half Kuzma to Davis the
Fast break can be lethal for the Lakers and they've cut the deficit to six and the Warriors lose this game
They're gonna look at this quarter and recognize. This is where it happened carelessness on the offensive end
Another turnover, but Warriors get it back Wiggins for three
Under two to play third quarter here in this playing game Kuzma backdoor lamp is good
Timeout goal in state
This one has been terrific the marquee matchup of the plan is not disappointed
Curry tied up gets an inside the green green to Wiggins Wiggins hard off the glass won't go the tip is up and good
Boy Wiggins playing with a force tonight at both ends. He's got 15. It's a six-point Warriors lead
Matthews cuts looking for Davis
James three-pointer puts it in
His first three-pointer
Up the night and it's a three-point game, but you look at the post-up play where Wiggins had a one-on-one
He shoots a fade away one leg of shot now knocks down a three
That's good defense sometimes you just got to give credit to greatness. Oh curry beautiful pass
But Wiggins couldn't handle it and Kuzma comes the other way
Lobbitt and Davis throws it down Lakers within one
Boy is it fun to hear a large crowd the noise of that once again curry on the drive
Curry for three that's good Steph Curry from way downtown his fifth three-pointer of the night
You know how tough a shot that was I?
Mean other great NBA players
Can't shoot that he is one of a kind
On that type of pass it sprint catch and fire
James back to order Caruso another backdoor cut leads to a layup
But there's more space on the floor now that the traditional center is out
And so there's more cutting avenues no fouls to give him for the Lakers dream on green wide open for three
Welcome back to the State Farm NBA play-in tournament here with coach Frank Vogel Frank
What do you attribute that lockdown defense in the third quarter you really forced a bunch of warriors turnovers?
Yeah, that's a pretty good most of the night
You know we wrap suited up a little bit in that quarter
We know that steps quarter to get going still hit a few bombs on us
You know we got to live with that but you know our guys are motivated and you know
We take pride in the more deep into the league and we're gonna need it down a stretch here
Do or die fourth quarter a playoff birth on the line you've got Steph Curry on the other side
What do you tell your guys got to execute? Okay?
Just that's what you got to worry about scooter our defensive coverage is and get a good shot every time down. Thank you so much
All right, you'll James the rebound after the beautiful feed to Davis to tie the game opening minute here fourth quarter
warriors
Largest lead was 13 early in the third
And the Warriors did a good job when Curry and Green rested in the first half
But this is danger zone right now James inside back shot missed it and Kevon Looney could not quite hold on
And it's Laker ball with 14 now on the shot clock
And I love this substitution of Dramon Green coming back in that's just a beautiful pass to Davis
You need to match Green's minutes with Davis
Kuzma trying to get free and they lob it into Kuzma over pool lays it up and in and the Lakers with their first lead of the night
How long does Steve Kerr leave Steph Curry out of this ballgame?
That's the ninth assists from LeBron James Mulder to pull
Bulls been excellent off the bench down the stretch of the regular season. It's a whole different ball game
Mulder harassed and stolen by Caruso the turnovers continued a mountain the second half of the Warriors
And this is where Wiggins was stationary that entire possession
He's got to be great when Curry rests James drives on Toscano Anderson lay a bench at home
Timeout Golden State
Wiggins battling with Matthews Matthews an excellent defender throughout his career Wiggins trying to draw foul didn't get the whistle
We said a lot about the late the Warriors turning the ball over you got to give credit to this Laker defense
They have increased the value and I think it starts with who you're playing so West Matthews
He has been intense as James goes in with the reverse
And there and there's more room on the floor
Now six-point lead that's a 19 point turnaround here on the second half Curry looking to Toscano Anderson driving layup
Offensive foul James draws the charge
Davis falls on top of them
And I think Steve Kerr may be challenging this and that's a block
It is going to be a challenge
So they'll challenge those guys will get up and we'll see what happens
Eight points five rebounds off the bench
It's only the 11th and 12th free throws of the game for Golden State
Second half so far
They haven't played Mantra's arrow. They haven't played Portland Tucker
They've gone with a very tight rotation
Steve Kerr has only played eight players
His team trails by five two and a half gone by in the fourth Caruso the drive
Davis the tip won't go to Toscano Anderson a rebound again Draymond Green contesting the shot
Curry back in the green
Davis on Curry green pass tried to thread the needle and turned it over I
Had beautiful feed to Matthews good transition defense though from the Warriors
Kuzma the drive can't finish
Wiggins barrels in the Matthews offensive foul
Boy what a call from Frank Volga to get West Matthews off the bench
He has really had an impact as a coach
You have to have guys that you trust that when it's when it matters most
I know exactly what they're going to do and West Matthews has been proven to be a competitor at a league level
And a guy that has no quit and he has come out and got it done on a defensive end especially this is why they signed him
It's his first year with the Lakers. He's 34 his 12th year in the league the Lakers are his seventh team
He's always been an excellent defensive player
tough fearless
Rob Polinka
Wanted to bring him for these kind of games. There's certain matchups. You need him defensively can also hit a three
Competitors only apply it's hard to find great competitors West Matthews is
Davis jump shot got it Anthony Davis has come alive in the second half
No Laker lead is seven
Curry for three answers
Steph Curry with a six three pointer. He's got 29
So they clean a whole side eliminate the help and allow Steph Curry to win his matchup one-on-one and Caruso was substituted out of the game
Curry on Davis isolated there on the elbow Wiggins looking to help pull comes over to help
Matthews inside Kuzma shot clock at four Kuzma tough fallaway shot in and out
Now the fight for the rebound goes to dream on green
Curry on the drive scoop layup he banks at home all with a sweet move from Curry
31 points and it's a two-point game
And
Pull just pushing Matthews out of the way
That's going to be the first team foul here on the fourth
No, Caruso harassing him true to insert it into the game Steph Curry knocks down to three gets a rhythm and keeps them off balance turns the corner
Spectacular finish before the contest an efficient game for Curry 10 of 18 from the field six of nine from three
Davis left alone for three got it Anthony Davis his first three-pointer of the night
He was all for five and it's back to a five-point Laker lead get a couple layups get a dunk and now the jump shot becomes a little bit
Easier he struggled from three-point range all season long
Just 26%
Well good find by James as Green tries to take away the role
Always chatting away you straight on green
Curry gets free drives inside scoop layup missed it. He thought he was hit Steve Kerr is furious
Here's James the other way long three-pointer
Carams out to Mulder
Jordan pull all beautiful crossover tried to jam it ball knocks loose out of bounds and it's going to be Warriors ball
That would have been quite the highlight for Jordan Paul
I'm giving him a point just for the move and he got fouled
How is that not a foul
While you're looking at me, I'm not roughing Wiggins pull on the inbound and it's back to three
Truder brings it up with 643 remaining
The Bronz James sitting right now
Well, he's at his minute limit I wonder if we'll see him again entry pass knocked away by dream on green
Pool ahead to Wiggins Wiggins drives floats it up shot is good
19 points for Wiggins and it's back to one timeout LA
Marv Albert the greatest basketball announcer of all time
Was impact on aspiring broadcasters is immeasurable
Congratulations. Thanks for a spectacular career Marv Albert
And I'm one of those guys three years with Marv Albert as a partner
Congratulations legend
Paul misses screen dives Kuzminow comes up with it
Just passed the midway point of the fourth Truder draws the foul shot won't go
I'm just trying to imagine you as a head coach of the Lakers right now
Which the looks you would be given LeBron James like basically asking him are you are you ready yet?
No, I wouldn't be giving him dirty looks I'd be giving that
Whoever's in charge of the minutes police. I'd be like
Come on now. We'll give them off tomorrow
in the next day as
Caruso is gonna come back in
to the game
Truder has struggled tonight just two of 11 from the field
But it's the free throw Lakers back up to
Caruso will come in and Matthew sits 11 minutes for Matthews. He made his presence felt
I think the key obviously was the Lakers activity, but I think Frank Vogel found for this game
Davis at five playing huge minutes already up to 36 and
Going to West Matthews
Was a huge factor
In their swarming defense
Truder goes one for two
Caruso back in the guard Curry finds Wiggins Wiggins gets inside draws the contact and banks at home chance for a three-point play
Big plays from Wiggins on both ends of the floor tonight
An unselfishness of Steph Curry takes the double team gets rid of the basketball
Wiggins aggressive turns the corner and if you anybody on a lake is not defending Curry
You have to pull all the way over so he doesn't have ability to catch and finish
Wiggins wants to get the victory get back in the playoffs
He's only been in the playoffs once in his first six years in a league that was five games in the first round with Minnesota in 2018
He has had a terrific season
He's played 71 of the 72 games in the regular season and here in the playing
21 points on 10 of 18 from the field
He's available every game every year. He plays all the time as durable as any player in this league
Kuzma back out the shooter shot clock at three puts up the three shot won't go one of the foul Davis the offensive rebound back up and banks at home
But there's an awful lot of contact
Not just on the shot, but also Davis's rebound and finished Anthony Davis discarded people Curry reverse
With the English off the glass a little more magic from Steph Curry. He's got 33
And LeBron James is coming back in
Schroeder drives inside Caruso missed a layup Curry the rebound
Curry to Wiggins
Jordan pulled nope they wave it off an offensive foul
Say on the screen set by Dremont Green not allowing the chase down contest
James will return three fouls on green
I
Credit to Anthony Davis for not giving up on the play so his effort to try to get to the shooter forced that call
That's 12 second-half turnovers for Golden State. They only had five in the first half
They led by 13 at halftime
Lakers have taken the lead here on the fourth. They've led by as many as seven right now all tied with four and a half to play
This is a tough play to guard the curl by Davis Davis knocked away another steal from Dremont Green and
Mulder in the front court
Three steals three blocks for green curry on the drive gets inside foul line jumper. No good
11 rebounds for Davis to go with 21 points
Mulder up and into Schroeder drives layup shot is good. Oh, what a tough shot from Schroeder and Dremont Green wanted to push off
Green's got to be careful with the referees he already has a technical tonight
Gets the pass from Curry
Pull for three puts it in
Warriors back up by one and that's where Green is great. You blitz Curry
And
You get it to green and he plays four on three
He's a great great decision-maker and it may boil down to just that
Other guys not named Curry making shots being ready and aggressive because the Lakers are forcing Curry to get rid of the basketball
Dennis Schroeder tries drives on Wiggins flips it up shot. No good rebound rebound Dremont Green
And here come the Warriors up one
with 315 remaining
Curry fakes Curry drives floats it up banks at home
Timeout Lakers
There's the upcoming national TV schedule T and T tomorrow Indiana and Washington
At 8 Eastern for the right to get into the playoffs then the ESPN on Friday
Memphis winning earlier tonight against San Antonio will play the loser of this game
And it'll be at 9 Eastern for more in these games visit nba.com or the nba app
This has been a thriller here at the Staples Center
Anthony Davis and the Lakers came back from 13 down took a seven-point lead here in the fourth
But step Curry erupting here in the fourth. He's got 35 for the game and it's the Warriors up three
And interestingly Frank Vogel decides to sit Schroeder and
reinsert Wesley Matthews I
Think it's the right move absolutely
They got to make an adjustment because the Warriors clearing aside for Curry
They have to recognize that defensively the Lakers do and be in position to help James looking to post up Baysmore
Squares and faces seven on the shot clock Wiggins looking to help James four on the 24 James Jumper short
Rebound Matthews back out to James past the Caruso corner three side of the backboard and Baysmore gets the rebound
Now talked about it earlier Wiggins forcing LeBron did it at shot
That's a shot you're willing to give up if you're the Warriors defensively against a bigger stronger
And Caruso's defense forces the turnovers Curry dribbles it out of bounds
So inside the Davis the runner
No good, but a foul. That's absolutely inexcusable on a turnover. They didn't get matched up
So Green had to rotate to the wide open Caruso and now Davis gets fouled
So Paul picks up his third and Anthony Davis will shoot free throws
Two for two tonight. It's only 74 percent during the season
Big second half for Davis
Only at five points at halftime
18 in the second half one point game under two and a half remaining
Curry on the drive the floater in the paint short Wiggins tips it but right to Davis
James running the floor
Past the Caruso back to James and he's fouled Dramon greed would not let him get a layup and James goes down
holding his head
The officials discussing
I think they're gonna take a look at it to see if it's a flagrant
And there's contact to the head of LeBron James
To be interesting to see the conclusion that they come up with here
But there's clearly with the right hand of Dramon green to the head
Goes up the block this is a huge call again because it will be free throws and possession as green picks up his fourth personal
But clearly to me there was contact on the head according to the rule, but not everything to the head is a flagrant foul
You need to make up your mind, sir. No, I I don't think it is one
I think it will be called one and I hate when games are decided on these like
Influenced by like these like they're trying to split the atom over there and just can we play ball?
This is a great game. Absolutely. You have covered every base by the way, my friend. Well done
Well James obviously shaken up by the play, so he's gonna get two free throws
Will he get two free throws and will they get possession and he's smart enough to make sure they know he's hurt
I'm gonna name my next son John go
Thank you, John bring some sanity back to the NBA
You know and again part of it. It's just such a crucial call for
I mean he's looking he's going up to block the shot hands down. I think what Steve said there's no wind up and
The impact is because James comes into him and I'm not gonna take I'm not gonna explain myself to the whole LA roster
Play ball
Well James will get the two free throws
I'm not good at Ripley lip reading, but I think he just said something about trouble scene
Though again as Steve Javi said it was an awkward fall and that made it look worse than it was and apparently got poked in the eye, too
My only problem with it. It wasn't a contest to the basketball. It was a contest to the face because he can't jump as well
I
Ties the game with 207 remaining
I've been there before squinting my eyes just in case I miss a free throw so I have an excuse. I've been there
Had a rough first half but has made huge plays here in the second half a triple double
Mrs.. The second
And a loose ball fouls gonna go against LeBron James Jordan pool did a good job pursuing that rebound
Really you look right now both teams are shooting the rest of the way
So you if you're gonna be physical defensive you have to be physical and disciplined also where you don't give up free throws
Each team with one timeout left that as Mark said both teams in the penalty
Bayes more to pull Wiggins green and Curry and an offensive foul ball on dream on green on the moving screen
West Matthews draws that turnover
Steve Kerr can't believe that call nor can green who picks up his fifth
And that's not illegal screen to me that's West Matthews selling the foul
he's had
Important impact on this second half
Caldwell Pope back up to James
Wiggins has done an excellent job defensively on him tonight
Shot clock at six James looking to get a running start now past to Caruso Caruso on the drive inside Davis for the slam
Lakers back up to with a minute and a half to play and Caruso has been outstanding outstanding
great find
Curry the drive looking to draw contact and he does but they say before the shot doesn't matter they're in the penalty
So two free throws for Curry to tie the game with 123 left
Well, they go back to putting Steph Curry into the pick and roll knowing they don't want to switch it
James came off touched it to Caruso who just
Caught it on a stampede to the basket and dropped it off to Davis
Anthony Davis who had an awful first half
Has come alive 25 points including
13 here in the fourth quarter as curry hits the free throw and played 41 minutes so far
12 rebounds as well and has made some excellent defensive plays in the second half this game has been so much about defense from both teams
Curry ties the game
137 points for Steph Curry
They get it to call well pulp almost lost it shot clock at seven
James two defenders on him to call well pulp inside. He's tied up by green throws it back up top James puts up the three
Brian James from downtown as the shot clock expires a
Desperation even the Lakers are up three
Green back to Curry Curry sets leans in knocked away get it back from Curry shot clock at seven
Bayes more on the drive kicks it out pull for three James the rebound with 32 seconds remaining
There's about a 10-second different shot clock and game clock. They don't have to foul
I'm LeBron James. I'm putting my head down and attacking
Lost the ball gets it back Matthews for three
Fight for the rebound tipped twice picked up by Paul 10 seconds remaining. I'm in a foul
I'm not letting them shoot a three. They have a timeout left, but we'll call it here
Curse trying to call it and finally he gets it Steve Kerr came to half court
The officials couldn't see him or clearly couldn't hear him and he gets the timeout with 2.1 remaining
We'll see if the officials look to see to perhaps put more time on the clock
They got a great look the last time by Jordan pool in the corner of a nice pass by Bayes more
LeBron James with the three-pointer had to throw it up the shot clock was expiring
It's a big-time shot
awful execution
Realizes that the clock went down the good chase down by curry and LeBron
Elevates and knocks down the biggest shot of the night. That's a 30-footer and you see Curry
Who's had that look on
Opponents faces after he knocks down threes the same look as LeBron James with a clutch shot
They're still talking about his
Difficulty seeing after taking that shot in the face from dream on green
All right guys obviously
Golden state needs a three-pointer here to try and force overtime
And for the Lakers there's not enough time for them to foul and not allow a three-pointer, correct?
It depends on where the ball is caught and in what position I
Wouldn't be surprised if curry
Is used to try to free somebody else up
Because of teams natural reaction to him
No matter what type of cut he makes and that guy defending the basketball
LeBron James in this scenario. I'd keep my eyes on curry
Days more to inbound
Pull coming free curry trying to get free lost the ball. That's it
The Lakers are in the playoffs
The Warriors need to play on Friday. What a thriller here at the Staples Center
What a show these two stars put on tonight LeBron James with his vision
Bothered after that shot from dream on green. It's the desperation heave that proved to be the game winner
Offsetting the 37 points from Steph Curry
Lakers will play Phoenix on Sunday
The Warriors will play the Grizzlies on Friday night to keep their season alive and the respect from the two former MVPs
Warriors with an opportunity, but a defensive play ends this one and that's perhaps appropriate with all the terrific defense we saw tonight
This is he didn't even catch it in rhythm
That's just unbelievable just as the shot clock expired and he was blind
James with 22 points 11 rebounds tennis cysts and the game-winning three-pointer is with Rachel
LeBron
Congratulations on the win nice little celebration there with Anthony Davis
Yes, sir. You already know
What does this mean to you guys to be officially in the play-in bracket and the playoff bracket and to do it with this kind of
Win tonight over a team that has really been such a huge rival for you over the second half of your career
Well, I mean going into the postseason. I think it's two of the hottest teams. I think we were winner of five
They were winner of seven or eight or whatever the case may be
So both teams playing at a high level and we knew that they're gonna come up to our floor and give everything they had
You know, they hit us in the mouth in the first half and we just had to respond and we did that on defensive end and got some great
Contributions from guys off the bench and we all you know chipped in for this way
We got to talk about that shot you hit with about a minute left the three you didn't even look in rhythm there
What were you thinking is the ball left your hands?
you know just
I put in a lot of work in my game, you know, you know after you know drape my finger to the eye
I was literally seeing three three rims out there. So I just shot at the middle one and I was able to
Grace the man above I was able to knock it down
What in doubt go for the middle rim
What did it feel like when you were down there on the floor when you took that hard fall?
Were you worried that you wouldn't be able to continue in the game or have more problems?
You know, I've been there before
You know, I've been poking I before you know on a rim collision like that
So just try to keep my composure, you know, it's gonna be pretty sore tonight. I know that for sure
But we have a few days until we do until we know when we'll go to Phoenix, but
It's a big time win for us and I definitely wasn't leaving the floor no matter if I had to
You know put a pirate patch on my eyes. So I love this team. I love to compete
One big rivalry down with this win tonight, but you've got another one to go with an old friend in Chris Paul
You mentioned going to Phoenix and facing the Suns. What do you think that matchup is gonna be like?
You know, they played extremely well all year and they deserve to you know host, uh, you know home court in the first round and
CP you know played at an MVP
caliber year all year
Book, you know Aiden has grown all year and they've given those guys a supporting cast around them
So, you know, we know what we're gonna get out of CP. We know how good
You know, how great CP is how great book is
Upcoming surgeons from you know from Aiden
You know, but it's the other guys as well that we got to make sure we can on because they've been playing extremely well all year
And that's why they've been the second best team in the West. Thank you so much for Brian. Congratulations. We'll see you in Phoenix